Curriculum vitae Adriana Carla Maziero Camarotto

Adriana Carla Maziero Camarotto

Technologist in Business and Management www.linkedin.com/in/adriana-maziero-camarotto

Mobile Number: 07738771515 e-mail: adriana.camarotto@gmail.com

I had achieved a University Degree in Business and Management (2013). Co-founder (2013) of the extinct Tricam Embedded Systems company, where I was responsible for the administrative and financial areas. I attended the workshop EMPRETEC in 2015 (the United Nations - UNCTAD entrepreneurial education program). I'm also a mentor Technovation Challenge, a worldwide entrepreneurship and technology challenge that encourages girls to develop mobile apps that solve a social problem through programming and entrepreneurship. I have been mentoring several teams (junior and senior) since 2016, including mentoring the South American Champion team in 2018 of the challenge. I have passion for entrepreneurship, technology, volunteering. I have Residence Card, and EU Scheme Pre-settlement permit. I can work and Leave to remain in UK.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Business Model Canvas; business plan; strategic planning; Microsoft PowerPoint; Microsoft Office; Microsoft Excel; video editing; Design thinking.

CERTIFICATIONS

EMPRETEC (UNCTAD); Strategic Planning (UNOESC); PEIEX (UNOESC); Design Thinking (UNOESC), Pre-Incubated Business Training (NIT / UNOESC); Startup Weekend 2018 (UNOESC); HTML5 + Bootstrap Front End Programming Workshop for Beginners 2019 (UNOESC). 5DCC – Five Days Coding Challenge 2022 (Code Institute), Discover's Path Conectar 2022 (Rocketseat).

LANGUAGES SKILLS

Portuguese – native English – second language

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

03/2022 - present - Tesco Pharmacy - Wells, UK - www.tesco.com

MEDICINE COUNTER ASSISTANT As a medicine counter assistant (starter) in a Pharmacy I am someone who is a team player learning technical skills with a strong customer focus to accurately dispense medication for our customers according to the Standard Operating Procedures. I am responsible for advising on the range of Pharmacy services available and take time to understand the customer's needs, explaining the benefits of the products in a way they understand. I respond to customer queries in relation to prescription medicines, informing the Pharmacist of any complaints. I offer information to costumers, on common ailments, symptoms, only selling products that are right for them in a confident, friendly and professional manner, providing to our customers with a great service, and ensure we trade safely and legally to making them want to visit our Pharmacy again.

As a trainee I am responsible for completing corporate and departmental training and Keeping up to date with legal and professional developments in pharmacy.

11/2020 – 03/2022 – Tesco – Ltd – Shepton Mallet, UK – www.tesco.com

As COSTUMER ASSISTANT I used to work in the ready meal department, where the best before dates are really sensitive, so I pay double attention to the dates and products rotation to assure the best for the customers. I am building good relationships with colleagues in a great team spirit. As part of this great team, I am focused on delivering all my department routines following company policies and adhering to health and safety guidelines, to assure that customers leave the store having experienced a great shopping.

10/2019 - 03/2020 Skills Direct Ltd - Shepton Mallet, UK - www.skillsdirectltd.com

As **OPERATOR MACHINE** — as a temporary employee I perform necessary pre-operation activities to ensure proper equipment start up and operation on multiple pieces of equipment. Test operation of machines periodically. Housekeeping and sanitation. As MANUFACTURING OPERATIVE/PACKERS as a temporary employee I work working in a busy production environment. The role consists of the following: Working on packings lines and following client specific packing designs; Loading food materials, adhering to site food safety and health and safety at all times, Palletising, wrapping and labelling products; Quality Control checks; Weighing and counting ingredients.

12/2013 – 05/2019 - Tricam Sistemas Embarcados - Luzerna – Brazil

ADMINISTRATIVE MANAGER — As an Administrative Manager my objective was the relationship with internal (employees) and external (customers) audiences. As it was a family business, I did everything from sales; caring for the company image; coffee making and keeping the premises clean and hygienic; technology update control (time management software and ERP- Enterprise Resource Planning); admissions; layoffs; accounting, financial and cash flow management; stock control; strategic and marketing planning; internal process management, and everything in between. One of the achievements was the development and sale of a modular product to one of the major customers with a view to the international market, resulting in increased system sales, reduced time and cost of product maintenance for the customer, reduced warranty costs and maximized user experience for this customer's products. www.comunidade.startse.com/in/tricam-sistemas-embarcados

01/2013 – 12/2014 - Atelier Adriana Camarotto - Luzerna – Brazil - www.facebook.com/adrianacamarottoatelier **ENTREPRENEUR AND CRAFTSWOMAN** - This project was a dream come true since childhood. By implementing Atelier, I was able to put into practice everything I learned in the Entrepreneurial Technology Course. I was responsible for the whole process of creation and development of handcrafts, dissemination and sales of them. I gave workshops that taught the best techniques I learned throughout my life, and that made the pieces I produced to have in the community great recognition for quality and beauty. I took courses with renowned teachers, including international, so that my pieces could reach the level of excellence that I always tried to achieve.

04/2012 - 04/2013 - UNOESC - Joaçaba - Brazil - www.unoesc.edu.br

UNDERGRADUATE RESEARCH FELLOW

Undergraduate research fellowship "Commercial Feasibility Study of Small Wind Generators in the face of the New Energy Scenario." Sponsored by Support Fund for the Maintenance and Development of Higher Education (in portuguese: FUMDES - Fundo de Apoio à Manutenção e ao Desenvolvimento da Educação Superior). Held during the undergraduate degree in Technology in Management Processes and Entrepreneurship at the Applied Social Sciences Area, at the undergraduate level at the University of Western Santa Catarina - UNOESC Project under the guidance of Prof. Dr. Ardinete Rover.

11/2010 – 12/2011 - SENAI / SC - Luzerna – Brazil - https://www.sc.senai.br/cursos

GRADUATION SECRETARY ASSISTANT - As responsible for the alumni and some of the professor's interests in the three graduation courses SENAI had to offer, I was the direct link between the two, organizing events, looking after enrollment, graduation ceremonies, organization of alumni relevant documentation, to feed the school administration system (enroll students, courses, issue certificates, attendance, grades, student production/hour); control the use / location of rooms and audio visual equipment; control school documentation (files, records, etc.); disseminate course programming; attend internal and external public; issue and sign school transcripts, statements and other requested documents. I also worked in the Tech courses that were periodically offered by the institution, with a shorter duration than a regular grad course, I was also responsible for enrolment, documentation and Certificate emissions for those courses.

06/1999 — 09/2005 — PUCRS/ SAJUG (Free Juridic Assistance Service) - Porto Alegre - Brazil www.pucrs.br/direito/a-escola/servicos/sajug-servico-de-assistencia-juridica-gratuita

SECRETARY - As the main secretary for the service, I did face to face with the external client that came in with any given Juridic demand and I was responsible to refer the client to the respective Student Lawyer who would take care of that particular case and I was also responsible to file away any relevant documentation about the case. Attributions: To attend students, teachers and external public; Control distribution and reservation of physical space for academic activities in the preparation of the inaugural class and SAJUG projects; Issue various documents (letters, minutes, scheduling, reports, certificates, yearbook, indicators and sectoral metrics, among others); Organize the archive of documents and materials of the Secretariat; Receive, check and forward documents via protocol system; Control the loan of equipment and materials; Perform specific activities of the Unit; Receive, register and submit student application forms; Schedule hearings and distribute to teachers; help with university enrolment, client registration, assistance with student reception planning.

EDUCATION

2011 – 20013 - UNOESC - Joaçaba – Brazil - www.unoesc.edu.br

GRADUATION IN TECHNOLOGIST IN BUSINESS AND MANAGEMENT

According to the educational institution, the technology course in management processes focuses on the job market focused on practical activities that instigate a business vision, with emphasis on organizational processes and business. The student is prepared to develop and implement administrative strategies, gain market insight, formulate business plans for new ventures and existing organizations, able to make decisions that improve levels of business competitiveness.

Curriculum vitae Adriana Carla Maziero Camarotto

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

2016 - 2020 - TECHNOVATION CHALLENGE - https://technovationchallenge.org/

MENTOR - As a volunteer mentor to the Technovation Challenge, encourage girls to learn how to program to develop mobile apps that solve social problems in their communities and around the world. I teach them sustainable business models and business plans for their startups. In 2018 the GirlsUp team, mentored by me, was a South American champion in the Technovation Challenge Junior category, with Life4down App, and in 2019 this same team was a senior semi-finalist in the Technovation Challenge.

08/2017 - 06/2019 - SEBRAE SC

MEMBER OF LIDER PROGRAM - Member of the Lider Program team, promoted by the SEBRAE / SC initiative in partnership with the 12 cities that make up the Midwest Santa Catarina Municipalities Association (AMOOC), which aims to promote the mobilization, qualification and integration of regional leaders for the elaboration of a regional development agenda.

Link: ttps://www.ammoc.org.br/noticias/index/ver/codMapaItem/42458/codNoticia/466539

03/2016 - 12/2018 - ACIOC - Associação Comercial e Industrial do Oeste Catarinense -

MEMBER - Within the **ACIOC-NJE** (Young Entrepreneur Nucleus), I was the coordinator of the first edition of the Young Entrepreneur Nucleus Award. Developed several activities such as drafting the NJE Award participation notice, marketing planning, strategic planning, event organization and social actions, among others. I participated in training focused on entrepreneurship.

Link: http://www.acioc.com.br/premio-nje

08/2015 - 08/2017 - ITL - Incubadora Tecnologica Luzerna - http://www.incubadoraluzerna.com.br

CHAIRMAN OF THE ADVISORY BOARD INCUBATED COMPANIES - I was responsible for presiding monthly, in ordinary and extraordinary sections; Ensure compliance with the institution's internal regulations, suggest plans and programs, standards, criteria and other instruments; Propose Goals Plan and Board of Directors and forms of performance appraisal of incubated companies and projects, in view of the reports presented and analyses made by the Board, using a standardized methodology; Request and propose to the director routine operational demands.